You know not to look at anyone on the Tube, but I guess he saw me. I guess he looked at all of us, as his hand hovered over the detonation switch. I've often wondered: What was he thinking? Especially in those final seconds. I know it wasn't personal. He didn't set out to kill or maim me, Gill Hicks. I mean -- he didn't know me. No. Instead, he gave me an unwarranted and an unwanted label. I had become the enemy. To him, I was the "other," the "them," as opposed to "us." The label "enemy" allowed him to dehumanize us. It allowed him to push that button. And he wasn't selective. Twenty-six precious lives were taken in my carriage alone, and I was almost one of them. In the time it takes to draw a breath, we were plunged into a darkness so immense that it was almost tangible; what I imagine wading through tar might be like. We didn't know we were the enemy. We were just a bunch of commuters who, minutes earlier, had followed the Tube etiquette: no direct eye contact, no talking and absolutely no conversation. But in the lifting of the darkness, we were reaching out. We were helping each other. We were calling out our names, a little bit like a roll call, waiting for responses. "I'm Gill. I'm here. I'm alive. OK." "I'm Gill. Here. Alive. OK." I didn't know Alison. But I listened for her check-ins every few minutes. I didn't know Richard. But it mattered to me that he survived. All I shared with them was my first name. They didn't know that I was a head of a department at the Design Council. And here is my beloved briefcase, also rescued from that morning. They didn't know that I published architecture and design journals, that I was a Fellow of the Royal Society of Arts, that I wore black -- still do -- that I smoked cigarillos. I don't smoke cigarillos anymore. I drank gin and I watched TED Talks, of course, never dreaming that one day I would be standing, balancing on prosthetic legs, giving a talk. I was a young Australian woman doing extraordinary things in London. And I wasn't ready for that all to end. I was so determined to survive that I used my scarf to tie tourniquets around the tops of my legs, and I just shut everything and everyone out, to focus, to listen to myself, to be guided by instinct alone. I lowered my breathing rate. I elevated my thighs. I held myself upright and I fought the urge to close my eyes. I held on for almost an hour, an hour to contemplate the whole of my life up until this point. Perhaps I should have done more. Perhaps I could have lived more, seen more. Maybe I should have gone running, dancing, taken up yoga. But my priority and my focus was always my work. I lived to work. Who I was on my business card mattered to me. But it didn't matter down in that tunnel. By the time I felt that first touch from one of my rescuers, I was unable to speak, unable to say even a small word, like "Gill." I surrendered my body to them. I had done all I possibly could, and now I was in their hands. I understood just who and what humanity really is, when I first saw the ID tag that was given to me when I was admitted to hospital. And it read: "One unknown estimated female." One unknown estimated female. Those four words were my gift. What they told me very clearly was that my life was saved, purely because I was a human being. Difference of any kind made no difference to the extraordinary lengths that the rescuers were prepared to go to save my life, to save as many unknowns as they could, and putting their own lives at risk. To them, it didn't matter if I was rich or poor, the color of my skin, whether I was male or female, my sexual orientation, who I voted for, whether I was educated, if I had a faith or no faith at all. Nothing mattered other than I was a precious human life. I see myself as a living fact. I am proof that unconditional love and respect can not only save, but it can transform lives. Here is a wonderful image of one of my rescuers, Andy, and I taken just last year. Ten years after the event, and here we are, arm in arm. Throughout all the chaos, my hand was held tightly. My face was stroked gently. What did I feel? I felt loved. What's shielded me from hatred and wanting retribution, what's given me the courage to say: this ends with me is love. I was loved. I believe the potential for widespread positive change is absolutely enormous because I know what we're capable of. I know the brilliance of humanity. So this leaves me with some pretty big things to ponder and some questions for us all to consider: Is what unites us not far greater than what can ever divide? Does it have to take a tragedy or a disaster for us to feel deeply connected as one species, as human beings? And when will we embrace the wisdom of our era to rise above mere tolerance and move to an acceptance for all who are only a label until we know them? Thank you. (Applause)
Ya saben qué es no mirar a nadie en el metro, pero supongo que él sí que me vio. Creo que nos miraba a todos nosotros, mientras su mano rondaba el interruptor de la detonación. A menudo me he preguntado: ¿En qué estaría pensando? Especialmente en esos segundos finales. Sé que no era personal. No se dispuso a matarme o mutilarme a mí, Gill Hicks. Quiero decir, él no me conocía. No. En cambio, me colocó una etiqueta injustificada y no deseada. Me había convertido en el enemigo. Para él, yo era el "otro", el "ellos" en lugar de "nosotros". La etiqueta de "enemigo", le permitió deshumanizarnos. Esto le permitió apretar ese botón. Y él no era selectivo. Acabó con 26 preciosas vidas solo en mi vagón y yo casi fui una de ellas. En el tiempo necesario para tomar aliento, nos sumergimos en una oscuridad tan inmensa que era casi tangible. Lo que imagino que debe ser vadear por alquitrán. Nosotros no sabíamos que éramos el enemigo. Estábamos en un grupo de pasajeros que, minutos antes, había seguido las reglas de comportamiento en el metro: no hay contacto visual directo, no se habla absolutamente, ninguna conversación. Pero al desaparecer la oscuridad, procurábamos llegarnos. Nos ayudábamos entre sí. Estábamos diciendo nuestros nombres, un poco como pasar la lista, en espera de respuestas. "Soy Gill. Estoy aquí. Estoy viva. Bien." "Soy Gill. Aquí. Viva. Bien." No conocía a Alison. Pero oía sus señales cada pocos minutos. No conocía a Richard. Pero me importaba que él sobreviviera. Todo lo que compartí con ellos fue mi nombre. Ellos no sabían que yo era jefa del departamento en el Consejo de Diseño. Y aquí está mi amado maletín, También rescatado esa mañana. Ellos no sabían que publiqué revistas de arquitectura y diseño, que era miembro de la Royal Society of Arts, que vestía de negro, lo que aún hago, que fumaba puritos. Ahora ya no fumo más. Bebía ginebra y miraba TED Talks, por supuesto, sin imaginar que un día iba a estar yo aquí, manteniendo el equilibrio sobre mis piernas protésicas dando una charla. Yo era una mujer australiana joven haciendo cosas extraordinarias en Londres. Y no estaba preparada para poner fin a todo eso. Estaba tan decidida a sobrevivir que con mi pañuelo até torniquetes en la parte superior de mis piernas, y tapo todo y todos salen, para enfocar, para escucharme a mí misma, guiarme por el instinto. Bajé la tasa de respiración. Elevé mis muslos. Me mantuve en posición vertical y luché contra el impulso de cerrar los ojos. Me aferré durante casi una hora, una hora contemplando la totalidad de mi vida hasta ese momento. Tal vez debería haber hecho más. Tal vez podría haber vivido más, visto más. Tal vez debería haber ido a correr, bailar, hacer yoga. Pero mi prioridad y mi enfoque siempre fue mi trabajo. Yo vivía para trabajar. Quién era yo en mi tarjeta de visita me importaba. Pero no importaba en ese túnel. En el momento en que sentí ese primer contacto de uno de mis rescatadores, yo fui incapaz de hablar, incapaz de decir siquiera una palabra pequeña, como "Gill". Les entregué mi cuerpo a ellos. Había hecho todo lo posible, y ahora estaba en sus manos. Entendí quién y lo que la humanidad realmente es, cuando vi por primera vez la marca de identificación que me dieron cuando me admitieron en el hospital. Y ponía: "Desconocido probablemente mujer." Desconocido probablemente mujer. Esas tres palabras eran mi regalo. Lo que me dijeron muy claramente era que mi vida estaba a salvo, simplemente por ser un ser humano. Diferencia de ningún tipo marcaron una diferencia en las medidas extraordinarias que prepararon los equipos de rescate para salvar mi vida, para salvar tantas vidas desconocidas como pudieron, y poniendo sus propias vidas en peligro. Para ellos, no importaba si yo era rica o pobre, el color de mi piel, si era hombre o mujer, mi orientación sexual, a quién voté, si tenía educación, si tenía confesión o si carecía de fe alguna. Nada importaba aparte de ser una preciosa vida humana. Me veo como un hecho vivo. Yo soy una prueba de que el amor incondicional y el respeto no sólo pueden salvar, sino que pueden transformar vidas. Aquí hay una imagen maravillosa de uno de mis rescatadores, Andy, y yo tomada el año pasado. Diez años después del suceso, y aquí estamos, abrazados. A lo largo de todo el caos, mi mano estaba agarrada con fuerza. Mi cara acariciada suavemente. ¿Qué sentí? Me sentía querida. Lo que me blinda contra el odio y la retribución, lo que me ha dado el valor de decir: esto termina conmigo es amor. Fui amada. Creo que el potencial para un cambio positivo generalizado es absolutamente enorme porque sé de lo que somos capaces. Sé lo hermoso de la humanidad. Así que esto me deja con algunas cosas bastante grandes para reflexionar y algunas preguntas para todos a tener en cuenta: ¿No es lo que nos une mucho más que lo que nos puede separar? ¿Tiene que pasar una tragedia o un desastre para que nos sintamos profundamente conectados como una sola especie, como seres humanos? ¿Y cuándo abrazaremos la sabiduría de nuestra era elevándose por encima de la simple tolerancia y pasando a aceptar a todos los que son sólo una etiqueta hasta que los conocemos? Gracias. (Aplausos)